<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Reflections</string>
    <string name="thanks">Thank you for participating in Reflections 2016 at Monrovia High!</string>
    <string name="reflections">Please turn in your submissions to
    your counselor by October 25, 2016.\n If you have questions
        email reflections@mhs.ptsa.groups.io \n or go to www.pta.org/reflections.</string>
    <string name="dance_text">DANCE CHOREOGRAPHY is the act of creating movement. The choreographer (student submitting entry) may
be the performer or one of the performers, but the choreographer does not have to perform in the entry.\n
2016-2017 Theme: What Is Your Story?
Consider the following styles and ensembles to portray your original choreography: Ballet, contemporary, ethnic
and folk, freestyle, hip hop, jazz, street dance, and tap.\n
Originality: Only new and original choreography inspired by the theme may be submitted. Each entry must be
the work of one student only.
Consider use of background song(s), props and the location to show a clear relation of the dance
choreography to the theme. An explanation of the origin of the dance and/or the significance of the
choreography might be a useful addition to the artist statement when submitting a dance choreography entry
that involves traditional, cultural or regional dances. Whether an entry displays formal dance technique or a
simple approach, it will be judged primarily on how well the student uses his or her artistic vision to portray
the theme, originality and creativity.\n
Copyright: Use of copyrighted material is prohibited. Plagiarized entries will be disqualified. Use of
background music must be cited on the student entry form.\n
Presentation: Video must not exceed 5 minutes in length and 1GB (one gigabyte) in file size.\n
Ideas for Audio/Visual Quality: Use a tripod to hold the camera still. Make sure there is plenty of lighting,
especially if shooting indoors. Turn off all noise-making devices in the room (air conditioners, fans, telephones,
etc.). Record a short test and watch it. If needed, change the record volume or microphone location. Make
sure the background music (if any) is audible on the recording. Allow for two seconds of silence at the
beginning and end of your recording.\n
Packaging:\n
• Accepted video file formats include: AVI, MOV, MPG, MPEG, MP4, WMV, FLV and F4V.\n
• Label video file and CD/USB Drive with your State, Arts Category, Grade Division, Last Name, First Name
(Example: PA.DANCE.PRI.SMITH.JOHN)\n
• Submit dance video and student entry form according to your PTA’s instructions.\n
State Specific Instructions: Students must follow state specific requirements and instructions.</string>
    <string name="film_text">FILM PRODUCTION is the process of making a film. The producer (student submitting the entry) is not
required to appear in the film but if the student chooses to, a camera tripod may be used. All screenwriting,
directing, camera/filming and editing must be done by the student producer. PowerPoint presentations are
prohibited.\n
2016-2017 Theme: What Is Your Story?\n
Consider the following styles to portray your original work of fiction or nonfiction:\n
• Animation: Demonstrates motion by sequencing still objects or using computer-generated graphics.\n
• Narrative: Tells a fictional story developed by the student.\n
• Documentary: Presents facts and information.\n
• Experimental: Explores movement, light and montage.\n
• Multimedia: Uses a combination of different contents (text, audio, still images, animation, etc.).\n
Originality: Only new and original videos inspired by the theme may be submitted. Each entry must be the original
work of one student only.
An explanation of the storyline and/or the significance of the film style might be a useful addition to the artist
statement. Whether an entry displays use of technologies or a simple approach, it will be judged primarily on
how well the student uses his or her artistic vision to portray the theme, originality and creativity. Software
used to create an entry should only enhance and present the work, not provide the primary design.\n
Copyright: Entry may include public places, well-known products, trademarks or certain other copyrighted
material as long as that copyrighted material is nonessential to the subject matter of the piece and/or is a
smaller element of a whole. Use of background music must be cited on the student entry form.\n
Presentation: Video must not exceed 5 minutes in length and 1GB (one gigabyte) in file size.\n
Ideas for Audio/Visual Quality: Use a tripod to hold the camera still. Make sure there is plenty of lighting,
especially if indoors. Turn off all noise-making devices in the room (air conditioners, fans, telephones, etc.).
Record a short test and watch it. If needed, change the record volume or microphone location. Make sure the
background music (if any) is audible on the recording. Allow for two seconds of silence at the beginning and
end of your recording.\n
Packaging:\n
• Accepted video file formats include: AVI, MOV, MPG, MPEG, MP4, WMV, FLV and F4V.\n
• Label video file and CD/USB Drive with your State, Arts Category, Grade Division, Last Name, First Name
(Example: PA.DANCE.PRI.SMITH.JOHN)\n
• Submit video and student entry form according to your PTA’s instructions.\n
State Specific Instructions: Students must follow state specific requirements and instructions.</string>
    <string name="literature_text">LITERATURE is the art of writing. The author (student submitting entry) is a person who expresses their own
thoughts and ideas through the use of words. Authors submit a single literary work, handwritten or typed,
using grade-appropriate grammar, punctuation and spelling. Collections of literary work (such as poems and
short stories) are not accepted.\n
2016-2017 Theme: What Is Your Story?\n
Consider the following literary styles to portray your original work of fiction or nonfiction: Prose, poetry,
drama (screen play and play script), reflective essay, narrative, or short story.\n
Originality: Only new pieces of artwork inspired by the theme may be submitted. Each entry must be the work
of one student only.
An explanation of the storyline and/or the significance of the literature style might be a useful addition to the
artist statement. Whether an entry displays formal writing technique or a simple approach, it will be judged
primarily on how well the student uses his or her artistic vision to portray the theme, originality and creativity.
Spoken word audio recordings and illustrated entries including books with pictures drawn by the student
author are acceptable; however, only literary content is judged.\n
Copyright: Use of copyrighted material is prohibited. Plagiarized entries will be disqualified.\n
Presentation: Entry may be hand written or typed. Writing must not exceed 2,000 words.
Acceptable Use of Type, Dictation and Translation\n
• Be typed by another person as long as the original work or a copy of the original work is attached.\n
• Be dictated to another person and printed or typed in exact words as spoken by the student if the student
is in pre-school, kindergarten or 1st grade. (Transcribers should make every attempt to retain the same
level of language and accuracy that is reflected in the student’s original work).\n
• Students for whom English is not their first language may submit literature entries in their own language.
An interpretive translation in English must accompany the entry. Translators should make every attempt
to retain the same level of language and accuracy that is reflected in the student’s original work.\n
Packaging:\n
• Print Format: Number each page. Print on 8.5x11 paper (one sided only).\n
• Electronic Format: Save/scan word document as a single PDF. Label file with your State, Arts Category,
Grade Division, Last Name, First Name (Example: PA.DANCE.PRI.SMITH.JOHN)\n
• Label Cover Page/CD/USB Drive with your State, Arts Category, Grade Division, Last Name, First Name.
Submit literature and student entry form according to your PTA’s instructions.\n
State Specific Instructions: Students must follow state specific requirements and instructions.</string>
    <string name="music_text">MUSIC COMPOSITION is the process of creating a new piece of music. The composer (student submitting entry) is a
person who expresses their own thoughts and ideas through the use of sound. The student composer may submit an
entry performed by an individual or group and/or make use of a sound library generated performance of a composed
score. Student composers are not required to perform their composition. Middle and high school grade divisions require
music score/tablature/notation, either traditional or tablature.\n
2016-2017 Theme: What Is Your Story?\n
Consider the following musical styles and instruments to portray your original composition: A cappella, blues, choral,
country, electronic, hip hop, jazz, world music , musical, orchestral, pop, R&amp;B, religious, rock, symphonic/concert band
and traditional.
All instruments, sounds, styles and combinations are accepted. Software may be used to produce an audio recording
that does not include commercially pre-programmed imported MIDI or other source files. Entries containing algorithmic
composition techniques are not accepted. An explanation of the origin of the music and/or the significance of the music
style might be a useful addition to the artist statement when submitting a music composition that involves traditional,
cultural or regional instruments. Whether an entry displays formal composition technique or a simple approach, it will
be judged primarily on how well the student uses his or her artistic vision to portray the theme, originality and creativity.\n
Originality: Only new and original songs inspired by the theme may be submitted. Each entry must be the work of one
student only.\n
Copyright: Use of copyrighted material is prohibited. Plagiarized entries will be disqualified.\n
Presentation: Audio must not exceed 5 minutes in length and 1GB (one gigabyte) in file size. Videos are not accepted.\n
Ideas for Audio Quality: Do not place the recording device on top of an instrument(s) or speakers. Turn off all noisemaking
devices in the room (air conditioners, fans, telephones, etc.). Record a short test and listen to it. If needed,
change the record volume or microphone location. Allow for two seconds of silence at the beginning and end of your
recording.\n
Notation &amp; Score Required for Middle School &amp; High School Divisions Only. Notation software may be used to create a
score. Whether the score is handwritten or computer-generated, appropriate instrumentation and voicing are required
for the performance. Number each page. Print on 8.5x11 (one sided only) or save/scan score as a single PDF.\n
Packaging:\n
• Accepted audio file formats include: MP3, MP4, WMA, WAV, ACC (M4A) and FLAC.\n
• Label audio file, notation/score (if applicable) and CD/USB Drive with your State, Arts Category, Grade Division, Last
Name, First Name (Example: PA.DANCE.PRI.SMITH.JOHN)\n
• Submit music composition and student entry form according to your PTA’s instructions.\n
State Specific Instructions: Students must follow state specific requirements and instructions. </string>
    <string name="photography_text">PHOTOGRAPHY is the process of creating an image. The photographer (student submitting entry) is a person
who captures their own thoughts and ideas with a camera. By focusing on objects using various lenses, filters
and light sources, photographers may demonstrate the use of photographic techniques conventionally or
digitally.\n
2016-2017 Theme: What Is Your Story?\n
Accepted forms of photography include: A single photo, panoramic, photomontage (one seamless print of
multiple original photos), a multiple exposure, negative sandwich or photogram. Original black-and-white and
color images are accepted. Non-accepted forms of photography include: Entries with added graphics over the
image, including lettering, are not accepted. Original film (negatives or transparencies) and multidimensional
pieces are not accepted.\n
Originality: Only new pieces of artwork inspired by the theme may be submitted. Each entry must be the work
of one student only.\n
Consider use of objects, lighting and the location to show a clear relation of the photo to the theme. An
explanation of the photography process/form might be a useful addition to the artist statement. Whether an
entry displays use of technologies or a simple approach, it will be judged primarily on how well the student
uses his or her artistic vision to portray the theme, originality and creativity.\n
Copyright: Use of copyrighted material, including copyrighted cartoon characters or other such material, is not
acceptable in any photography submission, with the following exception:\n
Photographs may include public places, well-known products, trademarks or certain other copyrighted
material as long as that copyrighted material is incidental to the subject matter of the piece and/or is a
smaller element of a whole. The resulting work cannot try to establish an association between the
student and the trademark/business/material, or influence the purchase/non-purchase of the
trademarked good.\n
Presentation: Framed photos are not accepted. Matting is accepted.\n
• Print Photo: Must not exceed 11x14 inches, including matting. Mount on sturdy material such as
cardboard or poster board.\n
• Digital Photo: Must be high resolution (300 dpi or higher).\n
Packaging:\n
• Label back of print and digital photo file with your State, Arts Category, Grade Division, Last Name, First
Name (Example: PA.DANCE.PRI.SMITH.JOHN).\n
• Submit photography and student entry form according to your PTA’s instructions.\n
State Specific Instructions: Students must follow state specific requirements and instructions.</string>
    <string name="visual_text">VISUAL ARTS include many art forms that are visual in nature. The artist (student submitting entry) is a person
who captures their own thoughts and ideas to create a visual piece of art.\n
2016-2017 Theme: What Is Your Story?\n
Accepted forms of visual art include: Architecture (2D/3D), carpentry, ceramics, collages, photographic
collages (multiple photos cut/pasted), computer-generated image, crafts, design, dioramas, drawing, fiber
work, jewelry, kites, metal etching/punch work, mobiles, painting, printmaking, sculpture and wind chimes.\n
Originality: Only new pieces of artwork inspired by the theme may be submitted. Reproductions or enlargements
of other artwork are not accepted. Each entry must be the original work of one student only.\n
An explanation of the art form might be a useful addition to the artist statement. Whether an entry displays
use of formal technique or a simple approach, it will be judged primarily on how well the student uses his or
her artistic vision to portray the theme, originality and creativity.\n
Copyright: Use of copyrighted material, including any copyrighted cartoon characters or likeness thereof, is
not acceptable in any visual arts submission, with the following exceptions:\n
• Visual artwork may include public places, well-known products, trademarks or certain other copyrighted
material as long as that copyrighted material is incidental to the subject matter of the piece and/or is a
smaller element of a whole. The resulting work cannot try to establish an association between the student
and the trademark/business/material, or influence the purchase/non-purchase of the trademarked good.\n
• Visual arts collages may include portions of existing copyrighted works, such as photographs, magazine
clippings, internet images and type cut out of a newspaper, as long as those portions of copyrighted works
are used to create a completely new and different work of art.\n
Presentation: Framed artwork and artwork containing loose materials is not accepted. Matting is accepted.\n
• 2D artwork (e.g. painting) Dimensions must not exceed 24x30 inches, including matting. Paper entries
must be mounted on sturdy material.\n
• 3D artwork (e.g. sculpture) Must be able to move for display purposes. Must include packaging
materials and 3 photos of the entry (a combination of angles) for judging, ID and exhibition purposes
(entries that require assembling/repairing from transporting will be disqualified).\n
• Digital photo(s) of artwork: Must be high resolution (300 dpi or higher).\n
Packaging:\n
• Label back of artwork and photo file(s) with your State, Arts Category, Grade Division, Last Name, First
Name (Example: PA.DANCE.PRI.SMITH.JOHN).\n
• Submit artwork and student entry form according to your PTA’s instructions.\n
State Specific Instructions: Students must follow state specific requirements and instructions.</string>
    </resources>